<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Portfolio on Alfonso Magallon</title>
    <link>https://almagall.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Portfolio on Alfonso Magallon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://almagall.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Full Factorial DOE</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description>In this project, my goal was to explore and analyze a data set with the factors of concentration, temperature, and catalyst to see its affect on yield (response variable).
Link to complete project on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Predicting Heart Failure</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project, my goal was to explore a clinical dataset to create a machine learning model that can predict patient heart failure survival. By exploring the data, the aim will be to select the most important features that can be used for a machine learning algorithm. Different machine learning algorithms will be created in order to evaluate the best performing model.
Link to complete project on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Retail Price Optimization</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>For this project my goal was to explore a dataset containing information on retail pricing in order to identify a method to optimize a balance of retail pricing and customer attraction.
Data was explored by analyzing relationships and creating visualizations to easily identify trends. I looked into the retail categories to compare them to each other as well as to other retail competitors. I used a Decision Tree regression model to make pricing predictions and to compare to actual pricing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I graduated from UCSD in 2020 with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in Human Biology. Ever since then, I journeyed into the biotech industry where I continue to find myself in at the current moment. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to work at great companies and expand my skills with each job. I&amp;rsquo;ve specifically worked in clinical lab technician, quality control, and research associate roles. Throughout all these roles, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized the tremendous value of data and its role in shaping the gene therapy, pharmaceutical, and biotech industry in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Other places to find me:
Platform Link E-mail: alfonso.m0010@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfonso-magallon-3a2321199 GitHub: https://github.com/almagall </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://almagall.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://almagall.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>Alfonso Magallon SUMMARY
Results-driven data professional with a strong background in the biotech industry (gene therapy, pharmaceutical, and medical device) and ongoing master&amp;rsquo;s degree in data science. Equipped with skill sets in programming languages, data manipulation, statistical analysis and modeling, to leverage background experience and pivot into a data-centered role and career to contribute to insights and delivery of actionable results.
EDUCATION
Eastern University - St. Davids, PA (online)
Master of Science – Data Science, Expected Graduation: June 2024</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
